http://www.nutreco.com/en/Corporate/legal-information/privacy-statement-general/

Legal information
Privacy statement general (English)
Legal information
Privacy statement general (English)
Privacy statement general (Spanish)
Privacy statement employees
Privacy statement applicants
Terms of use
PRIVACY STATEMENT FOR CUSTOMER, SUPPLIER AND BUSINESS PARTNER DATA
1. INTRODUCTION2. FOR WHICH PURPOSE DO WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?3. HOW LONG DO WE RETAIN YOUR PERSONAL DATA?4. WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?5. HOW ARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA SECURED?6. HOW CAN YOU EXERCISE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?7. CAN YOU WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT?8. HOW TO LODGE A COMPLAINT OR REPORT A DATA BREACH?9. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US?
1. INTRODUCTION
This Privacy Statement is applicable to the processing of all personal data belonging to consumers, customers, suppliers and business partners (“Business Partner” or “you”) by Nutreco N.V. based at Stationsstraat 77, Amersfoort, The Netherlands and any company directly or indirectly owned or controlled by Nutreco that you are interacting with or have a business relationship with (hereafter referred to as “Our Company”, “we” or “us”). This Privacy Statement is not applicable to business related data and/or data on companies.
Nutreco N.V. and the company directly or indirectly owned or controlled by Nutreco that you are interacting with or have a business relationship with, are responsible for the processing of your personal data. In this statement we describe who we are, how and for which purposes we process your personal data and all other information that may be relevant to you. In case you have any additional questions you can contact us via the contact details provided at the bottom of this statement. This Privacy Statement applies since May 24, 2018. The last modifications were made on May 24, 2018. This statement may change over time and the most up-to-date version is published on our website. If significant changes are being made, we will actively inform you.
2. FOR WHICH PURPOSES DO WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
Our Company will process your personal data when you do business with us, when you use our websites or apps or when you interact with us.
A. For answering your questions
If you get in touch with us, we will use your personal data in order to reply and answer your question(s).
For this purpose
we process your personal data for this purpose on the basis of your consent when you provide us with your personal data
we process – to the extent applicable – your name, contact details, your correspondence with us, and any other personal data which are necessary to answer your question.
B. For the development and improvement of products and/or services
We process your personal data in order to assess, analyse and improve our products and (customer) services. We use aggregated personal data to analyse customer behaviour and to adjust our products and services accordingly. When you use a Website or an App, enter or search data through a Website or an App; we also process your personal data to compile analytics reports. We use aggregated personal data to analyse customer behaviour and to adjust our products and services accordingly, to ensure that it is relevant to our customers. This means that we analyse how often you read our newsletters, how often you visit our Website or Apps, which pages you click on and what goods you purchase through our Website or Apps. We may purchase supplementary data from public sources to complement our database for the above purposes.
For this purpose
we process your information based on our legitimate interest to develop and improve our products and services
we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment and credit information, and correspondence with us. In addition, we process the personal data you entered into a Website or that were generated by the functionalities you used in a Website and the technical data from your device such as its IP-address, the pages you visited on our Websites, your click- and surf behaviour and the length of your session
If you choose to participate in our surveys, we may ask you to provide us with personal data. We may also use the personal data that you have provided in the survey for this purpose.
C. For the assessment and acceptance of a customer, supplier or business partner
When you get in contact with us, we will process your personal data for assessment and acceptance purposes, for example in order to confirm and verify your identity. Our Company will further process your personal data for other administrative purposes such as due diligence and screening against publicly available government and/or law enforcement agency sanctions lists.
For this purpose
We process personal data because this is necessary for the conclusion of a contract between you and us. Our Company cannot enter into contracts without obtaining the required information
We process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment and credit information and details of your correspondence with us.
D. For the conclusion and execution of agreement
When you have purchased a product or service from us as a customer, or when you work together with us as a supplier or business partner, we process your personal data for administrative purposes such as sending invoices and making payments. We also use your personal data in order to deliver or receive and administer our or your products or services. Our Company will process your personal data in order to further execute our agreement, including for the delivery of customer services. When you require access to Our Company’s premises, we process your personal data for screening purposes.
For this purpose
we process personal data because this is necessary for the conclusion of a contract between you and us. Our Company cannot enter into contracts without obtaining the required information
we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment and credit information and details of your correspondence with us.
E. For relationship management and marketing
We use the information stored in our customer database to send you suitable offers and newsletters, as well as to provide customer services, perform account management and communicate recalls. We also use your personal data for the development, execution and analysis of market surveys and marketing strategies
For this purpose
when sending you newsletters and/or other relationship management and marketing communications, we process personal data based on your consent. In addition, we process personal data based on our legitimate interest to improve our marketing strategies
we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name, contact preferences, payment information, order history and correspondence with us.
F. For business process execution and internal management
We process your personal data in the performance and organisation of our business. This includes general management, order management and management of our assets. Our Company also processes your personal data for its internal management. We provide central processing facilities in order to work more efficiently. We conduct audits and investigations, implement business controls, and manage and use customer, supplier and business partner directories. Also, we process your personal data for finance and accounting, archiving and insurance purposes, legal and business consulting and in the context of dispute resolution.
For this purpose
we process personal data based on our legitimate interest to maintain and improve sound business operations
we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name, payment and credit information, payment and order history, correspondence with Our Company and data generated during the performance of the agreement between you and Our Company.
G. For organizational analysis and development, management reporting and acquisition and divestures
At Our Company, we process your personal data in the preparation and performance of management reporting and analysis. We use aggregated/anonymised personal data to create management reports and to analyse our business. We conduct customer, supplier and business partner surveys to learn more about your views and opinions in preparation of our management reporting. We also process your personal data for management reporting purposes in the context of mergers, acquisitions and divestitures and in order to manage such transactions.
For this purpose
we process personal data based on our legitimate interest to maintain and improve sound business operations
we process your contact details such as address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment and order history, correspondence with us and the information you provide when responding to our surveys.
H. When you use our websites or apps
When you use our websites or apps, we process technical data about your device to offer you functionalities and to allow our administrators to manage and improve the performance of our websites and apps. If you enter data on our websites or apps, such as a product preference or your location to receive relevant information or functionalities, Our Company processes this data to provide you with the requested information or functionalities. Further, we process your personal data to allow you to save your data (such as preferences and products) to your saved items and to allow you to share these with others using the sharing options you have configured on your device.
For this purpose
we process personal data based on our legitimate interest to offer technically adequately working websites and apps and to improve their performance. In addition, we process personal data for marketing purposes by using marketing and social media cookies on our websites and apps, based on your consent.
we process the personal data you have entered into our websites and apps, or that is generated by the functionalities you have used on our websites and apps, and the technical data from your device such as its IP address, the internet browser you use, the pages you have visited on our websites, your click- and surf behaviour and the length of your session. Details of cookie functionalities are described in cookie notices on the respective websites and apps.
I. To allow you to connect with us
Our Company is active on social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and YouTube. When you contact Our Company via social media, we process your personal data in order to answer your questions and to respond to your messages.In addition, when you visit a 'Connect with us' screen on one of our Websites or Apps, you can contact us through a variety of communication channels. We provide you with our email address, for you to send us your feedback and suggested improvements, as well as our websites, Twitter, Facebook and YouTube details. When you click one of the corresponding icons we will refer you to the website or app of the applicable third party, whether this is your email provider or a social media platform.
For this purpose
we process personal data based on our legitimate interest to adequately respond to your questions and correctly refer you to our social media pages
we process the communication channel you have chosen to use to connect with us and the personal data you supply to Our Company. This includes your (user) name, address, email address and the personal data you have included in your message. In addition, when you click one of the buttons displayed, the relevant third party might place cookies on your device.
J. To monitor and investigate compliance
We monitor our processes to check compliance with our policies and regulations. During monitoring activities, your personal data may be accessed and viewed.
For this purpose
we may process your personal data based on our legitimate interest to monitor our internal processes and in order to comply with the law
any personal data that is stored in our systems may be accessed and viewed for compliance purposes. The personal data that are accessed and viewed will not be stored for compliance purposes, unless we need them to further investigate potential non-compliant behaviour
we do not retain your personal data for this purpose, unless they are linked to non-compliant behaviour. We will then retain the relevant personal data until the investigation or proceedings have been concluded.
K. To protect health, safety, security and to ensure integrity
At Our Company, we value your health, safety, security and integrity highly. We process your personal data in order to safeguard our employees, customers, suppliers and business partners. As such, we authenticate your access rights to our premises and may screen your personal data against publicly available government and/or law enforcement agency sanctions lists. We also process your personal data to protect Our Company and employee and customer assets.
For this purpose
we may process your personal data based on our legitimate interest to monitor our internal processes and in order to comply with the law
we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, ID card or passport details, car registration number, payment and order history, and your visiting history to our premises.
L. To comply with the law
In some cases, we process your personal data to comply with laws and regulations. This could, for example, be the case where tax or business conduct related obligations apply. In order to comply with relevant laws and regulations, we may need to disclose your personal data to government institutions or supervisory authorities.
For this purpose
we process your personal data in order to comply with the law
we process your contact details such as your address and email address, personal details such as your name and date of birth, payment information, payment and order history, and your chamber of commerce and VAT details and tax details.
M. When you participate in events or promotions
We send you emails with promotions and invitations to participate in events. If you choose to participate in one of these activities, we need your personal data to be able to announce and organise these. In addition, if you participate in any of these activities, we need your personal data to measure the response to events and/or promotions.
For this purpose
we process personal data based on your consent. You can withdraw your consent at any time, without this affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before withdrawal
we process your name, address, email address and your participation in the relevant event.
3. HOW LONG DO WE RETAIN YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
Our Company generally shall retain Business Partner Data only for the period required to serve the applicable Business Purpose, to the extent reasonably necessary to comply with an applicable legal requirement or as advisable in light of an applicable statute of limitations.
Promptly after the applicable storage period has ended, the Data shall be:
(i) securely deleted or destroyed; or(ii) anonymized; or(iii) transferred to an Archive (unless this is prohibited by law or an applicable records retention schedule)
4. WHO HAS ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA?
Access to your personal data within Our Company
As a global organisation, data we collect may be transferred internationally throughout Our Company’s worldwide organisation. Your personal data may be exchanged with the group that Our Company belongs to, our shareholder and associated companies, for administrative purposes and so that we can have a complete overview of your contacts and contracts with the group that Our Company belongs to. We may also exchange your data in order to offer you a complete package of services and products.
Our Company’s employees are authorised to access personal data only to the extent necessary to serve the applicable purpose and to perform their jobs.
In some cases, your personal data may be transferred to a country that does not provide an adequate level of protection of personal data. However, Our Company has taken measures to ensure that your personal data is adequately protected as Binding Corporate Rules are applicable throughout the group that Our Company belongs to.
Access to your personal data by third parties
Third parties may have access to your personal data where relevant for the provisioning of their products or services to Our Company.
When third parties are given access to your personal data, Our Company will take the required contractual, technical and organisational measures to ensure that your personal data are only processed to the extent that such processing is necessary for the purpose of processing agreed with Our Company. The third parties will only process your personal data in accordance with applicable law.
If personal data is transferred to a third party in a country that does not provide an adequate level of protection of personal data, we will take measures to ensure that your personal data is adequately protected, such as entering into EU Standard Contractual Clauses with these recipients.
In other cases, your personal data will not be supplied to third parties, except when required by law.
5. HOW ARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA SECURED
In our opinion and based on our risk assessment, we have taken adequate safeguards to ensure the security of your personal data. In our assessment we have considered the risks of accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss, damage, alteration, unauthorised disclosure or access, and other forms of unlawful processing (including, but not limited to unnecessary collection) or further processing.
6. HOW CAN YOU EXERCISE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS?
You have the right to request access or an overview of your personal data, and under certain conditions, rectification and/or erasure of personal data. In addition, you may also have the right of restriction of processing concerning your personal data, the right to object to processing as well as the right to data portability.
To invoke your privacy rights, please contact us by using the contact details at the bottom of this Privacy Statement. Keep in mind that we may ask for additional information to verify your identity.
7. CAN YOU WITHDRAW YOUR CONSENT?
Once given, you may always withdraw your consent. Please keep in mind that withdrawal does not have retrospective effect and the withdrawal of your consent is only possible in case you first have given your consent. Please contact us to withdraw your consent by using the contact details at the bottom of this Privacy Statement.
8. HOW TO LODGE A COMPLAINT OR REPORT A DATA BREACH?
If you have a complaint about the use of your personal data by Our Company, or if you have become aware of a data breach by Our Company, you can lodge a complaint or report a data breach via the contact details at the bottom of this statement. Besides lodging a complaint with Our Company, you are also able to lodge a complaint with your local data protection supervisory authority.
9. HOW CAN YOU CONTACT US?
If you have any questions about the way we process your personal data, please read this statement first. For additional questions, remarks, compliments or complaints, please contact the privacy officer of Our Company at privacy@nutreco.com.
Follow us on
General conditions
Privacy
Terms of use
Sitemap
Contact
Employees
